<aspects>
  <aspect name="Genomics">
    <subtitle>Genome annotation</subtitle>
    <icon-image>model/images/genomics.gif</icon-image>
    <large-image>model/images/genomics.gif</large-image>
    <intro-text>
      The gene structures and other genome annotations in RatMine are 
			provided by a variety of curated source databases including RGD, 
			NCBI and Ensembl.
    </intro-text>
    <tile-name>model/genomics.jsp</tile-name>
    <aspect-source name="RGD" url="http://rgd.mcw.edu"/>
	<aspect-source name="Ensembl" url="http://www.ensembl.org/Rattus_norvegicus/Info/Index"/>
  </aspect>

  <aspect name="Quantitative Trait Loci">
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	<icon-image>model/images/QTL_image_197x153.gif</icon-image>
	<large-image>model/images/QTL_image_197x153.gif</large-image>
	<intro-text>
  	Quantitative Trait Locus (QTL) is a polymorphic locus which contains alleles that differentially affect the 
		expression of a continuously distributed phenotypic trait. Usually it is a marker described by statistical 
		association to quantitative variation in the particular phenotypic trait that is thought to be controlled by the cumulative action of alleles at multiple loci.
		A disease-specific QTL in a rat model is obtained by intensive genetic crossing and analysis and is expected 
		to contain one to many genetic elements that would be contributing to the phenotype in the rat. An affected 
		strain (showing the phenotype) is crossed with an unaffected strain (lacking the phenotype), the progeny are 
		genotyped and phenotyped and through statistical techniques, a correlation is made between a particular genotype 
		and the phenotype being measured.
	</intro-text>
	<tile-name></tile-name>
	<aspect-source name="QTL" url="http://rgd.mcw.edu/rgdweb/search/qtls.html?100"/>
  </aspect>

  <aspect name="Single Nucleotide Polymorphism">
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	<icon-image>model/images/QTL_image_197x153.gif</icon-image>
	<large-image>model/images/QTL_image_197x153.gif</large-image>
	<intro-text>
  		Single Nucleotide Polymorphism brought to you by Ensembl.
	</intro-text>
	<tile-name></tile-name>
	<aspect-source name="Ensembl" url="http://www.ensembl.org/Rattus_norvegicus/Info/Index"/>
  </aspect>


  <aspect name="Proteins">
    <subtitle>Protein and proteomics&lt;br/&gt;data</subtitle>
    <icon-image>model/images/proteins.png</icon-image>
    <large-image>model/images/proteins.png</large-image>
    <intro-text>
      RatMine includes protein data such as sequences, family associations, 
			domain structures and gene associations downloaded from the UniProt Knowledgebase.   
    </intro-text>
    <tile-name>model/proteins.jsp</tile-name>
    <aspect-source name="UniProt" url="http://www.uniprot.org"/>
  </aspect>

  <aspect name="Gene Ontology">
    <subtitle></subtitle>
    <icon-image>model/images/geneOntology.png</icon-image>
    <large-image>model/images/geneOntology.png</large-image>
    <intro-text>
      The Gene Ontology (GO) project is a collaborative effort to address 
			the need for consistent descriptions of gene products in different databases.  
			GO collaborators are developing three structured, controlled vocabularies 
			(i.e. ontologies) that describe the molecular functions, biological processes 
			and cellular components of gene products in a species-independent manner.  GO 
			annotations for Rattus norvegicus, supplied by the Rat Genome Database, have been 
			loaded into RatMine and linked to the corresponding genes such that the information 
			available for each gene includes a list of its GO annotations.
    </intro-text>
    <tile-name>model/GO.jsp</tile-name>
    <aspect-source name="Gene Ontology Consortium" url="http://www.geneontology.org/"/>
  </aspect>

  <aspect name="Disease">
    <subtitle>Disease Ontology</subtitle>
    <icon-image>model/images/do.png</icon-image>
    <large-image>model/images/do.png</large-image>
    <intro-text>
			The Rat Genome Database Disease Ontology (DO) is a controlled, 
			hierarchical vocabulary based on the National Library of Medicine's 
			Medical Subject Headings (MeSH).  RGD manually assigns DO terms to rat 
			genes, QTLs and strains, human genes and QTLs and mouse genes based on data 
			from primary research articles.   DO annotations for Rattus norvegicus, 
			supplied by RGD, have been loaded into RatMine and linked to the corresponding 
			genes such that the information available for each gene includes a list of its DO annotations.
    </intro-text>
    <tile-name>model/DO.jsp</tile-name>
  </aspect>  

    <aspect name="Pathway Ontology">
    <subtitle></subtitle>
    <icon-image>model/images/pw.png</icon-image>
    <large-image>model/images/pw.png</large-image>
    <intro-text>
			The Pathway Ontology (PW) is a controlled biological vocabulary currently under 
			development at the Rat Genome Database.  The goal of the Pathway Ontology is to 
			capture the various kinds of biological networks, the relationships between them 
			and the alterations or malfunctioning of such networks within a hierarchical structure. 
			The four nodes are: classic metabolic pathways, regulatory pathways, signaling pathways 
			and disease pathways for complex human conditions.  RGD manually assigns PW terms to rat, 
			mouse and human genes based on data from primary research articles.   PW annotations for 
			Rattus norvegicus, supplied by RGD, have been loaded into RatMine and linked to the 
			corresponding genes such that the information available for each gene includes a list of its PW annotations.
    </intro-text>
    <tile-name>model/PW.jsp</tile-name>
    <aspect-source name="Pathway Ontology" url="http://rgd.mcw.edu/wg/pathway?100"/>
  </aspect> 
  
    <aspect name="Mammalian Phenotype Ontology">
    <subtitle></subtitle>
    <icon-image>model/images/mp.png</icon-image>
    <large-image>model/images/mp.png</large-image>
    <intro-text>
			The Mammalian Phenotype (MP) Ontology is being developed as a community 
			effort to provide standard terms for annotating phenotypic data.  The MP 
			Ontology has a hierarchical structure that permits a range of detail from 
			high-level, broadly descriptive terms to very low-level, highly specific terms.  
			RGD manually assigns MP terms to rat genes, QTLs and strains, and human genes and 
			QTLs based on data from primary research articles.   MP annotations for Rattus norvegicus, 
			supplied by RGD, have been loaded into RatMine and linked to the corresponding 
			genes such that the information available for each gene includes a list of its MP annotations.
    </intro-text>
    <tile-name>model/MP.jsp</tile-name>
    <aspect-source name="Mammalian Phenotype Ontology" url="http://www.informatics.jax.org/searches/MP_form.shtml"/>
  </aspect>
  
</aspects>
